Preliminary Inventory of the Latviesu Centrala Komiteja Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Latviesu Centrala Komiteja records,
1919-1949
48017
Latviesu Centrala Komiteja
145 manuscript boxes, 4 card file boxes, 4 motion picture film reels, 4 microfilm reels (63 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoranda, reports, correspondence, registration forms, printed matter, and motion picture film, relating to conditions in Latvia under Soviet and German occupation, and to Latvian displaced persons during and after World War II. Also available on microfilm (199 reels).
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (199 reels).
Historical Note
Latvian émigré organization.
Scope and Content Note
Memoranda, reports, correspondence, registration forms, printed matter, and motion picture film, relating to conditions in Latvia under Soviet and German occupation, and to Latvian displaced persons during and after World War II. Also available on microfilm (199 reels).
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Latvia.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Latvia.; Latvia--History--1918-1940.; Latvia--History--1940-1991.
Genres and Forms of Material
Moving-pictures.
Container List
- Materials relating to Latvian soldiers held in a prisoner of war camp at Putlos, Germany (under Allied occupation), and to events in Latvia during both Soviet and Nazi rule in Latvia, 1941-1945. (Box 1)
  - Summary of lectures (Folder 1: 1)
  - Correspondence, bulletins, and reports relating to the Information Branch, 1st division, Latvian Legion, 1945 (Folder 1: 2-3)
  - Documents compiled in 1945 for a history of the Latvian Legion. (Folder 1: 4)
    Includes verbatim, typewritten copies of articles from the Latvian press during the German occupation, as well as copies of orders issued by the German military administration for Ostland
  - Documents pertaining to events in Latvia under Soviet and German occupations, including verbatim, typewritten copies of articles from the Latvian press, and also of directives issued by Soviet and German authorities (Folder 1: 5-6)
  - Documents concerning resistance activities in concentration camps in Latvia, 1943-1945 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Miscellaneous reports and chronicles, 1945. (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
    Includes bulletins, correspondence, news summaries, personal accounts, serial issue, music and lyrics to prisoners' songs, and some holograph illustrations of camp life
  - Information bulletin, 1st division, Latvian Legion, and news summaries prepared for prisoners, 1945 (Folder 2: 3-4)
  - Lectures and papers by and for prisoners, 1945 (Folder 2: 5)
- Latvian refugee camps in Germany: rosters of camp inhabitants. (Box-folder 3: 1-3)
  Lists of names compiled by Latvian ex-POWs upon their release from Putlos camp, and on the basis of a search for relatives throughout camps in Germany
- Demographic information concerning the inhabitants of Latvia during the period under the first Soviet occupation, 1940-1941
  - Statistical data concerning those killed (Folder 3: 4)
  - Statistical data concerning those arrested and deported (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Statistical data concerning those arrested and missing (Folder 4: 2)
  - Statistical data concerning those missing (Folder 4: 3)
  - Statistical data concerning dead partisans (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Statistical data concerning dead civilians (Folder 5: 2)
  - Statistical data concerning those deported (Folder 5: 3)
- Records of the Latvian gymnasia (secondary schools) at Kiel and Rendsburg (Box 6)
  - Brief history of the Kiel Gymnasium (Folder 6: 1)
  - Minutes, teachers' council meetings, Kiel Gymnasium
    - 1945-1947 (Folder 6: 2)
    - 1947-1949 (Folder 6: 3)
  - Minutes, school council meetings, Kiel Gymnasium, 1946 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Student records, Kiel Gymnasium, 1945-1949 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Duplicates of student certificates, Kiel Gymnasium, 1946-1948 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Brief history of the Rendsburg Gymnasium. (Folder 6: 7)
    Includes printed copy of graduation prayers
  - Minutes, teachers' council meetings, Rendsburg Gymnasium, 1945-1947 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Student records, Rendsburg Gymnasium, 1945-1947 (Folder 6: 9)
  - Duplicates of student certificates, Rendsburg Gymnasium, 1947 (Folder 6: 10)
- Camp periodicals and exile publications (Box 7)
  - Vestis, published by the Latvian Camp Committee at Fischbach, Germany
    - Nos. 6-50 (No. 18 missing), 1946 (Folder 7: 1-4)
    - Nos. 4-30, (Nos. 5,7,12) 1947 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Latvija, published at Camp Churchill, Lehrte, Germany. Nos. 281-336 (nos. 289,316,321 missing), 1947; nos. 338-346, 1948 (Folder 8: 2)
  - Briva Latvija, published by Gustav Celmins, 1947-1948 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Atbalss, published in Neuotting, Germany
    - 1946-1947 (incomplete) (Folder 8: 4)
    - 1948 January-June (Folder 8: 5)
  - Nameja Gredzens, published by Latvian POWs, Putlos, Germany, 1945. (Box 9)
    Includes some typescript originals with holograph illustrations
    - June (No. 1) (Folder 9: 1)
    - July (Nos. 2-6) (Folder 9: 2)
    - August (No. 8 and three unnumbered issues) (Folder 9: 3)
    - December (No. 14) (Folder 9: 4)
  - Dundsdorfs, Edgars, Latjijas Zeme, Iedzivotaji un Saimnieciba Prieks Leilas Emigracijas: Statistiskos Datos, Lübeck, 1945 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Illustration of woman in Latvian national costume, 1945 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Calendar, in Latvian, Esslingen, Germany, 1947 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Vilks, A., Latviesi Beglu Gaitas, Germany, 1947 (Folder 9: 8)
  - The Problem of Latvian Displaced Persons, Latvian Central Committee in Western Germany, Germany, 1947 November (Folder 9: 9)
  - Shall Latvians Perish?, Latvian National Council, Esslingen, Germany, 1948 September (Folder 9: 10)
- Demographic information concerning the inhabitants of Latvia during the period of the first Soviet occupation, 1940-1941. Official forms, with text in both German and Latvian, compiled by the Latvian Statistics Board during the German occupation of Latvia, and on the basis of a statistic sheet in use as of January 15, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Statistics concerning those arrested and deported, and those registered as arrested and missing, with some other categories interspersed, all listed by family name
    - A (Folder 10: 1-5)
    - A (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - B (Folder 11: 2-5)
    - B (Box 12-13)
    - B (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
    - C (Folder 14: 4)
    - C (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - D (Folder 15: 3-4)
    - D (Box-folder 16: 1-4)
    - E (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    - F (Folder 17: 3-4)
    - H (Folder 17: 5)
    - I (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - J (Folder 18: 2-4)
    - J (Box-folder 19: 1-3)
    - M (Folder 19: 4-5)
    - M (Box-folder 20: 1-3)
    - N (Folder 20: 4-6)
    - O (Box-folder 21: 1-4)
    - S (Folder 21: 5)
    - S (Box 22-24)
    - S (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - T (Folder 25: 2-4)
    - T (Box-folder 26: 1)
    - U (Folder 26: 2-3)
    - V (Folder 26: 4-5)
    - Z (Box-folder 27: 1-4)
    - Z (Box-folder 28: 1-3)
    - M (Folder 28: 4-5)
    - M (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 29: 3)
  - Statistics concerning individuals categorized as partisans, grouped largely according to district
    - Riga (City) (Folder 29: 4)
    - Riga District (Folder 29: 5)
    - Riga District (Box-folder 30: 1-2)
    - Cesis District (Folder 30: 3-4)
    - Valka District (Box-folder 31: 1)
    - Liepaja District (Folder 31: 2)
    - Ventspils and Kuldiga Districts (Folder 31: 3)
    - Valmiera District (Folder 31: 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 32: 1-5)
      Includes statistics from Abrenes and Talsu Districts
    - Ilukste District (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - Jekabpils District (Folder 33: 2)
    - Tukums District (Folder 33: 3)
    - Madona District (Folder 33: 4)
    - Daugavpils District (Folder 33: 5)
    - Jelgava District (Box-folder 34: 1-3)
  - Statistics concerning dead and wounded partisans (Folder 34: 4)
  - Statistics concerning civilian deaths due to warfare (Folder 34: 5)
  - Statistics concerning deaths attributed to the actions of Soviet forces, and other unattributed deaths (Folder 34: 6)
  - Statistics concerning wounded police force members (Folder 34: 7)
  - Statistics listing names, but without indication of category (Folder 34: 8)
  - Statistics concerning individuals listed as having fled to the Soviet Union, having pro-Soviet sympathies, or being otherwise unaccounted for, largely from the Riga District (Box 35-38)
  - Statistics concerning individuals listed as arrested and disappeared, and for those arrested and deported, with some other categories interspersed. (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
    Includes data for the Riga District and other areas of Latvia
  - Statistics concerning individuals listed as having reappeared or returned, or otherwise found to be alive. (Folder 39: 3-5)
    Includes data from throughout Latvia
  - Statistics concerning individuals listed as arrested and disappeared, and for those arrested and deported, with some other categories interspersed. (Box-folder 40: 1-4)
  - Statistics concerning individuals listed as having fled to the Soviet Union, or having pro-Soviet sympathies, or being otherwise unaccounted for (Box 41)
    - Jelgava District (Folder 41: 1-4)
    - Tukums District (Folder 42: 1-3)
    - Bauska District (Folder 42: 4-5)
    - Talsu District (Box-folder 43: 1-3)
    - Kuldiga District (Folder 43: 4-5)
    - Ventspils District (Box-folder 44: 1-2)
    - Liepaja District (Folder 44: 3-4)
    - Aizpute District (Folder 44: 5)
    - Riga District (Box-folder 45: 1-5)
    - Cesis District (Box-folder 46: 1-2)
    - Madona District (Folder 46: 3-4)
    - Valmiera District (Box-folder 47: 1-4)
    - Valka District (Box-folder 48: 1-3)
    - Kalupe, Livanu, and vicinity (Folder 48: 4-5)
    - Daugavpils District (Box-folder 49: 1-3)
    - Jekabpils District (Folder 49: 4-5)
    - Ilukste District (Folder 49: 6)
    - Abrene District (Box-folder 50: 1-3)
    - Rezekne District (Folder 50: 4)
    - Rezekne District (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - Ludza District (Folder 51: 2-5)
    - Ludza District (Box-folder 52: 1-4)
    - Ludza District (Box-folder 53: 1-2)
  - Duplicate statistic sheets, of various categories and from different regions (Folder 53: 3-4)
  - Duplicate statistic sheets (Box 54-56)
  - Duplicate statistic sheets (Box-folder 57: 1-3)
  - Statistic sheets annotated as having been "withdrawn" (Folder 57: 4)
  - Statistics concerning individuals returning to Latvia after 1941 July 1 (Folder 57: 5)
  - Statistics concerning individuals returning to Latvia from the Soviet Union, and compiled principally on the basis of forms issued by the Reichskomissar for Ostland, 1942 April 11
    - Duplicates annotated as having been "withdrawn" (Folder 57: 6-7)
    - Riga District (Box-folder 58: 1-2)
    - Tukums District (Folder 58: 3)
    - Jekabpils and Madona Districts (Folder 58: 4)
    - Cesis, Valka, and Talsu Districts (Folder 58: 5)
    - Abrene, Daugavpils, Ilukste, and Rezekne Districts (Folder 58: 6)
    - Addresses unknown (Folder 58: 7)
    - Jelgava District and elsewhere (Folder 59: 1)
    - Valmiera District (Folder 59: 2-3)
    - Madona District (Folder 59: 4)
    - Cesis District (Folder 59: 5)
    - Valka District (Folder 59: 6)
    - Jelgava District (Box-folder 60: 1)
    - Aizpute, Kuldiga, Liepaja, Talsu, and Ventspils Districts (Folder 60: 2)
    - Bauska, Daugavpils, Ilukste, Jekabpils, Ludza, and Rezekne Districts (Folder 60: 3)
    - Valka District (Folder 60: 4-6)
    - Valka District (Box-folder 61: 1-4)
    - Ilukste District (Folder 61: 5)
    - Tukums District (Box-folder 62: 1-2)
    - Riga District (Folder 62: 3-4)
    - Daugavpils District (Box-folder 63: 1)
    - Ludza District (Folder 63: 2)
    - Abrene District (Folder 63: 3)
    - Rezekne District (Folder 63: 4)
    - Valmiera District (Folder 63: 5-6)
    - Valmiera District (Box-folder 64: 1)
    - Forms annotated as having been "withdrawn" (Folder 64: 2-4)
    - Riga District (Folder 64: 5)
    - Riga District (Box-folder 65: 1-3)
    - Bauska District (Folder 65: 4-5)
    - Bauska District (Box-folder 66: 1)
    - Jekabpils District (Folder 66: 2-4)
    - Jelgava District (Folder 66: 5)
    - Jelgava District (Box-folder 67: 1-4)
    - Ventspils District (Box-folder 68: 1)
    - Madona District (Folder 68: 2)
    - Kuldiga District (Folder 68: 3)
    - Liepaja and Aizpute Districts (Folder 68: 4)
    - Talsu District (Folder 68: 5)
    - Addresses unknown (Folder 68: 6)
  - Statistics concerning those individuals listed as having been deported, from the Riga District. Official forms, with text in German and English, compiled by the Latvian Statistics Board during the German occupation of Latvia, on the basis of a statistic sheet in use as of 1942 January 15 (Box 69-71)
  - Index cards with the names of individuals listed as having returned to Latvia from the Soviet Union
    - A-M
    - N-Z (Box 73)
    - Unsorted (Box 74)
- Rosters of the names of Latvians in displaced person and POW camps, mainly in Germany, 1945-1946. (Box 75)
  Includes some miscellaneous notes and correspondence
  - Putlos (Folder 75: 1-3)
  - Heide, Vesterburg, and elsewhere (Folder 75: 4-5)
  - Bavaria. Names listed as having been "screened" (Folder 75: 6)
  - Munich, Detmold, and elsewhere (Box-folder 76: 1-3)
  - Hamburg and Rheinberg (Folder 76: 4)
  - Other locations in Germany, Austria, France, and Italy (Folder 76: 5-6)
  - Amberg, Fischbach, Nuremberg, Wurzburg (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - Various other locations in Germany and Austria (Folder 77: 2-5)
- Photograph albums of scenes depicting Latvian displaced persons in Germany, 1947-1948 (Box 78)
  - YMCA Camp, Grafenau, 1947 (Folder 78: 1-2)
  - Camp Hochfeld near Augsburg, Germany, 1947 (Folder 78: 3)
  - Campt Haunstetten near Augsburg, Germany, 1947 (Folder 78: 4)
  - Holy Communion, Anna Church, Augsburg, Germany, 1947 (Folder 78: 5)
  - Confirmation ceremony, Esslingen, Germany, 1947 (Folder 78: 6)
  - Ligo festival and other scenes, Camp Hochfeld, 1947 (Folder 78: 7)
  - YMCA/YWCA skiing courses, 1948 (Folder 78: 8)
- Materials relating to Latvian displaced person camps at Seedorf and Rotenburg, Germany, 1946-1949 (Box 79)
  - Roster of the names of discharged Latvian POWs, 1946 (Folder 79: 1)
  - Official notices, bulletins, and memoranda from British authorities, 1947-1949. (Folder 79: 2-3)
    Includes correspondence to and from camp leaders
  - Copies of training school certificates and other documents issued to camp residents, 1948 (Folder 79: 4)
  - Circulars issued by camp leaders, 1947-1949 (Folder 79: 5-6)
  - Correspondence between camp leaders and British authorities, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 80: 1)
  - Correspondence between camp leaders and refugee organizations, 1947-1948 (Folder 80: 2)
  - Minutes of meetings and other documents relating to the election of camp leaders and committee members, 1947-1948 (Folder 80: 3-4)
  - Copies of training certificates and other documents, 1947-1949 (Folder 80: 5)
  - Food supply records, including receipts and ration schedules, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 81: 1-4)
  - Minutes of committee meetings, 1946-1948 (Folder 82: 1)
  - Accounts and invoices, 1947-1948 (Folder 82: 2-4)
  - Minutes of auditors' meetings, 1947-1948 (Folder 82: 5)
- Miscellaneous materials relating to Latvians in the Leipzig area, 1945 (Folder 82: 6)
- Miscellaneous materials relating to Latvians in the Leipzig area, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 1-2)
- Materials relating to the Latvian displaced person camp at Hohnsen, Germany, 1945-1947
  - Minutes of committee meetings, 1945-1947 (Folder 83: 3-4)
  - General correspondence. (Box 84)
    Includes some miscellaneous documents
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 84: 1-3)
    - 1947 (Folder 84: 4-5)
  - Announcements, bulletins, and circulars (Box 85)
    - 1945-1946 (Folder 85: 1)
    - 1947 (Folder 85: 2)
- Materials relating to Latvian displaced person camps and colonies in the Braunschweig region, Germany, 1945-1948
  - General file, Hornburg camp, 1947 (Folder 85: 3)
  - Minutes of the Braunschweig district committee, 1946-1947 (Folder 85: 4)
  - General file, Braunschweig district committee, 1945-1947 (Folder 85: 5)
  - General file, Goslar and Bad Wurzburg colonies, 1946 (Folder 85: 6)
  - General file, Repner colony, 1946 (Folder 85: 7)
  - General file, Hallendorf camp, 1947 (Folder 85: 8)
  - General file, Braunschweig colony, 1946 (Folder 85: 9)
  - General file, Liebenburg camp, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 86: 1-2)
  - Minutes of the Liebenburg camp committee, 1946-1948 (Folder 86: 3)
  - Accounts of the Liebenburg camp committee, 1945-1948 (Folder 86: 4)
  - Instructions and circulars of the Liebenburg camp committee, 1947 (Folder 86: 5)
- Miscellaneous materials relating to Latvian displaced person camps in Germany, 1945-1948
  - Minutes of the camp committee and general meetings, Gauja camp, Melle, 1946-1947 (Folder 86: 6)
  - Accounts, Gauja camp, Melle, 1946-1947 (Folder 86: 7)
  - General file, Gauja camp, Melle, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 87: 1)
  - General file, Sarstedt camp, 1946-1947 (Folder 87: 2)
  - General file, Sarstedt dairy and horticultural school, 1946-1947 (Folder 87: 3)
  - "Operation Westword Ho" file, Hornburg camp, 1947 (Folder 87: 4)
  - General file, Schutzenberg camp at Detmold, 1945-1946 (Folder 87: 5)
  - Register of the names of individuals in transit through Schutzenberg camp, 1945 (Folder 87: 6)
- Materials relating to community courts having jurisdiction over Latvians in Germany, 1946-1947 (Box 88)
  - Oldenburg district
    - Register and alphabetical file of criminal cases (Folder 88: 1)
    - Register and alphabetical file of civil cases (Folder 88: 2)
    - Criminal case files (Folder 88: 3-4)
    - Civil case files (Folder 88: 5)
    - Ordinances and general file (Folder 88: 6)
  - Camp Ausma at Kleinkotz (Box 89)
    - Register of criminal cases (Folder 89: 1)
    - General file (Folder 89: 2)
    - Criminal case files (Folder 89: 3-6)
- Publications of the Latvian State Bureau of Statistics, 1924-1940 (Box 90)
  - Piensiamnieku sabiedribas 25 gadu atcerei, 1934 (Folder 90: 1)
  - Latvijas lauksaimnieciba 1939. gada, 1940 (Folder 90: 2)
  - Lauskaimniecibas skaitisana Latvija 1939. gada, 1940 (Folder 90: 3)
  - Piensiamnieku sabiedribas 30 gadu darbibas atcerei, 1939 (Folder 90: 4)
  - Lauku apdzivotas vietas, 1936 (Folder 90: 5)
  - Pagastu apraksti, 1935 (Folder 90: 6)
  - Vispariga sejumu un majlopu saitisana Latvija 1935. gada, 1938 (Box-folder 91: 1)
  - Latvijas lauksaimnieciba pec 1923. gada lauksaimniecibas skaitisanas zinam, 1924 (Folder 91: 2)
  - Vispariga sejumu un majlopu skaitisana Latvija 1937. gada, 1938 (Folder 91: 3)
  - Lauksaimniecibas rentabilitate, 1939 (Folder 91: 4)
  - Laukstradnieku dzivojamas telpas, 1937 (Folder 91: 5)
- Issuances of the Latvian government and military, 1919-1940 (Box 92)
  - Orders of the Minister of Defense, 1919 (Folder 92: 1)
  - Orders of the Minister of War
    - 1923 (Folder 92: 2)
    - 1924 (Folder 92: 3)
    - 1925 (Folder 92: 4)
    - 1926 (Folder 92: 5)
    - 1927 (Folder 92: 6)
    - 1928 (Folder 92: 7)
    - 1929 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - 1930 (Folder 93: 2)
    - 1931 (Folder 93: 3)
    - 1932 (Folder 93: 4)
    - 1933 (Folder 93: 5)
    - 1934 (Folder 93: 6)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 94: 1)
    - 1936 (Folder 94: 2)
    - 1937 (Folder 94: 3)
    - 1938 (Folder 94: 4)
    - 1939 (Folder 94: 5)
    - 1940. (Folder 94: 6)
      Includes materials relating to the liquidation of the Latvian army following the Soviet annexation of Latvia
  - Orders of the Commander-in-Chief and Chief Inspector of the Latvian army
    - 1919 (Folder 95: 1)
    - 1920 (Folder 95: 2)
    - 1921-1922 (Box-folder 96: 1)
    - 1923 (Folder 96: 2)
    - 1924 (Folder 96: 3)
    - 1925 (Folder 96: 4)
    - 1926 (Folder 96: 5)
    - 1927 (Folder 96: 6)
    - 1928 (Box-folder 97: 1)
    - 1929 (Folder 97: 2)
    - 1930 (Folder 97: 3)
    - 1931 (Folder 97: 4)
    - 1932 (Folder 97: 5)
    - 1933 (Folder 97: 6)
    - 1934 (Folder 97: 7)
    - 1935 (Folder 97: 8)
    - 1936 (Folder 97: 9)
    - 1937 (Folder 97: 10)
    - 1938 (Folder 97: 11)
    - 1939 (Folder 97: 12)
    - 1940 (Folder 97: 13)
  - Lists of promotions in the Latvian army, 1938-1940 (Folder 97: 14)
- Orders, reports, and other records relating to Latvian police and military units, 1941-1945 (Box 98)
  - Riga police force
    - 1941 July-December (Folder 98: 1)
    - 1942 January-February (Folder 98: 2)
    - 1942 March-June (Folder 98: 3)
    - 1942 June-September (Folder 98: 4)
    - 1942 September-December (Folder 98: 5)
  - 16th Zemgale Battalion, 1942 (Box-folder 99: 1)
  - 17th Vidzeme Battalion, 1942-1943 (Folder 99: 2)
  - 18th Kurzeme Battalion, 1942 (Folder 99: 3)
  - 20th Riga Battalion, 1944 (Folder 99: 4)
  - 22nd Daugava Battalion, 1942 (Folder 99: 5)
  - 23rd Gauja Battalion, 1942 (Box-folder 100: 1)
  - 22nd Talsu (formerly Venta) Battalion, 1942 (Folder 100: 2)
  - 28th Barta Battalion
    - 1942 (Folder 100: 3)
    - 1943 (Folder 100: 4)
    - Personnel and history (Folder 100: 5)
  - 266th E Battalion (Box 101)
    - 1943 (Folder 101: 1)
    - 1944 (Folder 101: 2)
  - 267th Battalion, 1944 (Folder 101: 3)
  - 268th Ergli Police Battalion, 1943-1944 (Folder 101: 4)
  - 271st Valmiera Battalion, 1943 (Folder 101: 5)
  - 271st F Battalion, 1944 (Folder 102: 1)
  - 272nd Daugava Battalion, 1943-1944 (Folder 102: 2)
  - 273rd Ludza Battalion, 1943 (Folder 102: 3)
  - 279th Battalion, 1943 (Folder 102: 4)
  - 280th Battalion, 1943 (Folder 102: 5)
  - 282nd-a Battalion, 1943 (Folder 102: 6)
  - 317th F Battalion, 1944 (Folder 102: 7)
  - 318th F Battalion, 1943 (Folder 102: 8)
  - 319th F Battalion, 1944 (Folder 102: 9)
  - 322nd F Battalion, 1944 (Folder 102: 10)
  - Casualty reports (Box 103)
    - 271st F Battalion (Folder 103: 1)
    - 313th Battalion (Folder 103: 2)
  - Police commanders' school, 1944 (Folder 103: 3)
  - General file of Colonel Osis, 1944 (Folder 103: 4)
  - Miscellaneous casualty reports, 1944 (Folder 103: 5-10)
  - Liaison Officer, Police and SS Headquarters, Liepaja, 1942 (Box-folder 104: 1)
  - Liepaja defense company, 1942 (Folder 104: 2)
  - Latvian Police, 25th Battalion, 1943 (Folder 104: 3)
  - Riga police reserves, 1944 (Folder 104: 4)
  - Miscellaneous police casualty reports, 1944 (Folder 104: 5)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 1944 (Folder 104: 6)
  - Riga and Liepaja Police Headquarters, 1944 (Folder 104: 7)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 1st Training Battalion, 1944 (Folder 104: 8)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 1st Battalion, 1944 (Folder 104: 9)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 2nd Training Battalion, 1944 (Box-folder 105: 1)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 2nd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 105: 2)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 3rd Battalion, 1944 (Folder 105: 3-4)
  - Riga Police Regiment, 4th Battalion, 1944 (Folder 105: 5)